Robert A. Jacobs Photographs
Robert A. Jacobs Photographs
1918-1949
Jacobs, Robert Allan.
5 linear ft.
Papers of the American architect, partner in New York City architectural firm, Kahn and Jacobs. Photograph folios of architectural projects; preliminary sketches.
149077
Biographical History
Robert A. Jacobs (1905-1993) was an American architect. Jacobs graduated from Amherst College and Columbia University's School of Architecture and spent his early years working for Le Corbusier in Paris and Wallace K. Harrison in New York. In 1940, he partnered with Ely Jacques Kahn to form Kahn & Jacobs (later in 1972 the firm merged with Hellmuth, Obata & Kassabaum). For forty years the firm designed and built numerous structures in New York City, including the American Airlines terminal at Kennedy International Airport, the office building One Astor Plaza, and the Municipal Asphalt Plant at 90th Street and East River Drive, named by the Museum of Modern Art as one of the best designs of the 1930s and 1940s.
Jacobs was a fellow of the American Institute of Architects and a member of the Architectural League of New York.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert A. Jacobs Photographs consist of photographs of Jacobs' architectural projects.
Arrangement of the Collection
Photographs are in no particular order.
Related Material
holds the papers of many notable architects. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; Jacobs, Robert Allan.; Kahn and Jacobs (New York, N.Y.); Architects -- United States.; Architectural drawing.; Architecture -- United States.; Architecture, American.; Architecture, Domestic.; Architecture, Industrial.; Architecture -- United States -- 20th century.; Photography, Architectural.; Photographs.; Sketches.; Architects.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Photographs
  - 550 7th Ave, 1925 (Oversize 1, Folder A2)
  - N.Y. Furniture Exchange, 1926 (Oversize 1, Folder A2)
  - Lefcourt Madison Building, 1925 (Oversize 1, Folder A2)
  - Lefcourt Empire Building, 1925-1926 (Oversize 1, Folder A2)
  - 79 Madison Ave., 1925 (Oversize 1, Folder A3)
  - 24-26 W. 40th St, 1924-1925 (Oversize 1, Folder A3)
  - 247-251 W. 35th St., 1924-1925 (Oversize 1, Folder A3)
  - 30 E. 42nd St (Oversize 1, Folder A3)
  - Ruben building (Oversize 1, Folder A3)
  - Cusack building, 1918 (Oversize 1, Folder A3)
  - Armion building, 1921 (Oversize 1, Folder A4)
  - Banco Construction Corp. building, 1925 (Oversize 1, Folder A4)
  - Bomzon building, 1925 (Oversize 1, Folder A4)
  - Borden building, 1923 (Oversize 1, Folder A4)
  - Federation building, 1927-1930 (Oversize 1, Folder A4)
  - 15-19 W. 39th St. building, 1925-1926 (Oversize 1, Folder A4)
  - 269 Madison Ave, 1926-1927 (Oversize 1, Folder A4)
  - 2 Park Ave. building, 1926-1931 (Oversize 1, Folder A4a)
  - Jay-Thorpe, Inc., 1919-1935 (Oversize 1, Folder A5)
  - Collins Oppenheim and Co., 1921-1924 (Oversize 1, Folder A5)
  - A. Simonson, Inc. (Oversize 1, Folder A5)
  - Steiger-Vedder Co (Oversize 1, Folder A5)
  - Shop of Hazel Kolman, Inc., 1926 (Oversize 1, Folder A5)
  - Eagle Pencil Co., 1923-1934 (Oversize 1, Folder A6)
  - Kahn and Feldman, 1919-1921 (Oversize 1, Folder A6)
  - Lehn and Fink, 1918 (Oversize 1, Folder A6)
  - Pinaud building, 1926-1930 (Oversize 1, Folder A6)
  - Merit Hosiery Co., 1926-1929 (Oversize 1, Folder A6)
  - Insurance Center building, 1926-1927 (Oversize 2, Folder A7)
  - Northwest corner of 37th St. and 6th Ave, 1925-1926 (Oversize 2, Folder A7)
  - Court Square building, 1926-1927 (Oversize 2, Folder A7)
  - 42-44 W. 39th St., 1937 (Oversize 2, Folder A7)
  - Southwest corner of Madison Ave. and 49th St, 1925-1926 (Oversize 2, Folder A8)
  - 1 W. 57th St (Bergdorf-Goodman building), 1927-1928 (Oversize 2, Folder A8)
  - U.S. Appraisers Stores, 1927-1929 (Oversize 2, Folder A8)
  - International Telephone building (Broad and Beaver Streets), 1928 (Oversize 2, Folder A8)
  - Lefcourt State building, 1927 (Oversize 2, Folder A8)
  - 334-336 7th Ave, 1927-1930 (Oversize 2, Folder A9)
  - Lefcourt Clothing Center, 1928 (Oversize 2, Folder A9)
  - Southeast corner of 29th St. and 5th Ave., 1928-1930 (Oversize 2, Folder A9)
  - Film center, 1928-1930 (Oversize 2, Folder A9)
  - 23 W. 45th St., 1928 (Oversize 2, Folder A9)
  - Eisig residence (Tuckahoe, NY) (Oversize 2, Folder C4)
  - Karpen residence (New Rochelle, NY), 1925 (Oversize 2, Folder C4)
  - Plaut residence (Elmsford, NY) (Oversize 2, Folder C4)
  - Tishman residence, 1927 (Oversize 2, Folder C6)
  - Liebman residence, 1927 (Oversize 2, Folder C6)
  - Benjamin residence (New York, NY), 1930 (Oversize 2, Folder C7)
  - Equitable Trust Co., 1929-1931 (Oversize 2, Folder C7)
  - Kolman residence (New York, NY) (Oversize 2, Folder C7)
  - Dr. Marcus A. Rothschild office (Oversize 2, Folder C7)
  - Andrews residence (Connecticut), 1940 (Oversize 3, Folder C12)
  - Coigne log cabin (New Jersey), 1941 (Oversize 3, Folder C12)
  - Ettinger residence (Connecticut), 1942 (Oversize 3, Folder C12)
  - Club house, Smullens, New Jersey, 1941 (Oversize 3, Folder C12)
  - Garfunkel residence (New York) (Oversize 3, Folder C12)
  - Rose residence (New York), 1947 (Oversize 3, Folder C12)
  - General Transportation Casualty and Surety Co. (Oversize 3, Folder C12)
  - Hospital for Joint Diseases, 1922-1928 (Oversize 3, Folder D1)
  - U.G.S. Project (Oversize 3, Folder D1)
  - New York City Garage and Air Raid Shelter, 1941 (Oversize 3, Folder D1)
  - National Urban League (Oversize 3, Folder D1)
  - USO buildings, 1941 (Oversize 3, Folder D1)
  - Schiff Pavilion, Montefiore home, 1925 (Oversize 3, Folder D1)
  - Montefiore home, 1925 (Oversize 3, Folder D1)
  - Davidow residence (New York), 1927 (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - Harris residence (New York), 1924-1925 (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - Kahn residence (New York), 1919-1931 (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - Kahn residence (Elmsford, NY), 1919-1931 (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - Herman Younker residence (Elmsford, NY) (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - Ira Younker residence (Elmsford, NY) (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - A. Schweizer residence (New York), 1923 (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - Riesenfeld residence (New York), 1923 (Oversize 3, Folder E1)
  - Maillard's (Chicago), 1924-1925 (Oversize 3, Folder E2)
  - Cincinnati Mayflower Shop, 1941 (Oversize 3, Folder E2)
  - Kridel residence (New York) (Oversize 4, Folder E3)
  - Hellman residence (New York) (Oversize 4, Folder E3)
  - Van Cleef and Arpels, Inc., 1929-1931 (Oversize 4, Folder E4)
  - Leron, Inc., 1931 (Oversize 4, Folder E4)
  - Voice of America building (Oversize 4, Folder E4)
  - 120 Wall St., 1930 (Oversize 4, Folder E4)
  - Glen Oaks Golf and Country Club, 1929 (Oversize 4, Folder E4)
  - Bricken building, 1929-1930 (Oversize 4, Folder E4)
  - Bonwit Teller, 1940 (Oversize 4, Folder E5)
  - Quaker Ridge Golf Club, 1926 (Oversize 4, Folder E5)
  - Fairview Country Club, 1925-1926 (Oversize 4, Folder E5)
  - Broadmoor Country Club, 1925-1926 (Oversize 4, Folder E5)
  - Calumet Club, 1925 (Oversize 4, Folder E5)
  - Scholle residence, 1948 (Oversize 4, Folder E5)
  - Reynolds Bar (Georgia), 1948 (Oversize 4, Folder E5)
  - Richard Hudnut, 1930-1935 (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Huyler's (Chicago), 1936 (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Huyler's (Buffalo), 1937 (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Burlington Mills Hosiery Factory (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Shearith-Israel Synagogue (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Carnegie Hall (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Continental building (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - 530 7th Ave. (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Holland Plaza building, 1929-1930 (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - 111 John St. building, 1929 (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Allied Arts building, 1929 (Oversize 4, Folder E6)
  - Greenebaum apartment (New York) (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Jacob Ruppert Distributing Plant, 1942 (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Jacobs residence, 1940 (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Southeast corner of Broadway and 39th St., 1930-1931 (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Northeast corner of Broadway and 38th St., 1930-1931 (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Satenstein residence (New York), 1946 (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Fort Greene houses (Brooklyn, NY) (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - War housing project (Rome, NY) (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Housing projet (Mineville, NY) (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Lexington Park Project, 1942 (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Gowanus houses (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Carver houses (Oversize 5, Folder E7)
  - Arsenal building (New York), 1925 (Oversize 5, Folder E9)
  - Millinery Center building (New York), 1925 (Oversize 5, Folder E9)
  - Park-Murray Corporation (Oversize 5, Folder E9)
  - Parents' Magazine office, 1940 (Oversize 5, Folder E9)
  - American Iron and Steel Exhibit (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - 30 E. 42nd St. (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Mausoleums (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Morgenthau residence (New Jersey) (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Northeast corner of 5th Ave. and 31st St. (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Morgenthau residence (New York) (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Charles Kaye buildings (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - L. P. Hollander and Co. (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Longchamps Restaurant, 1949 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - 498 7th Ave. (before alteration) (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - 500 7th Ave. (before alteration) (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Pix Theatre (Longchamps), 1939 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Stauffer Chemical (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Southeast corner of Lexington Ave. and 57th St., 1930 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Paramount Annex, 1930 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Northwest corner of 3rd Ave. and 44th St., 1930 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - 16 Desbrosses St., 1938 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - 119-121 Watts St., 1938 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Cullman residence (New York), 1941 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Hoffman residence (New York), 1942 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Marshall residence (New York), 1941 (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - Spiegelberg residence (New York) (Oversize 5, Folder E10)
  - American Institute of Architects Exhibition, 1936 (Oversize 6, Folder F2)
  - General Cigar building, New York World's Fair, 1939 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Design for service station (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Design for department store (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Shelton Looms showroom, 1928-1929 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Yardley and Co., Ltd. showroom, 1933-1934 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - E. R. Squibb and Sons executive offices, 1929-1933 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - E. R. Squibb and Sons sales office, 1929-1933 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Kohler Company building, 1932-1933 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Johns-Manville building, 1933 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Sidney Blumenthal and Company (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Strauss Mausoleum, 1929-1930 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Borden building executive offices, 1920-1923 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - New York City Department of Sanitation, 1937 (Oversize 6, Folder F3)
  - Preliminary sketches, 3 folios (Oversize 7)
Alphabetical index of projects
1 W. 57th St (Bergdorf-Goodman building) OS 2-A8
2 Park Ave. building OS 1-A4a
15-19 W. 39th St. building OS 1-A4
16 Desbrosses St. OS 5-E10
23 W. 45th St. OS 2-A9
24-26 W. 40th St OS 1-A3
30 E. 42nd StOS 1-A3 OS 5-E10
42-44 W. 39th St. OS 2-A7
79 Madison Ave. OS 1-A3
111 John St. building OS 4-E6
119-121 Watts St. OS 5-E10
120 Wall St. OS 4-E4
247-251 W. 35th St. OS 1-A3
269 Madison Ave OS 1-A4
334-336 7th Ave OS 2-A9
498 7th Ave. (before alteration) OS 5-E10
500 7th Ave. (before alteration) OS 5-E10
530 7th Ave. OS 4-E6
550 7th Ave OS 1-A2
29th St. and 5th Ave., southeast corner OS 2-A9
37th St. and 6th Ave, northwest corner OS 2-A7
3rd Ave. and 44th St., northwest corner OS 5-E10
5th Ave. and 31st St., northeast corner OS 5-E10
A. Simonson, Inc. OS 1-A5
Allied Arts building OS 4-E6
American Institute of Architects Exhibition OS 6-F2
American Iron and Steel Exhibit OS 5-E10
Andrews residence (Connecticut) OS 3-C12
Armion building OS 1-A4
Arsenal building (New York) OS 5-E9
Banco Construction Corp. building OS 1-A4
Benjamin residence (New York, NY) OS 2-C7
Bomzon building OS 1-A4
Bonwit Teller OS 4-E5
Borden building OS 1-A4
Borden building executive offices OS 6-F3
Bricken building OS 4-E4
Broadmoor Country Club OS 4-E5
Broadway and 38th St., northeast corner OS 5-E7
Broadway and 39th St., southeast corner OS 5-E7
Burlington Mills Hosiery Factory OS 4-E6
Calumet Club OS 4-E5
Carnegie Hall OS 4-E6
Carver houses OS 5-E7
Charles Kaye buildings OS 5-E10
Cincinnati Mayflower Shop OS 3-E2
Club house, Smullens, New Jersey OS 3-C12
Coigne log cabin (New Jersey) OS 3-C12
Collins Oppenheim and Co. OS 1-A5
Continental building OS 4-E6
Court Square building OS 2-A7
Cullman residence (New York) OS 5-E10
Cusack building OS 1-A3
Davidow residence (New York) OS 3-E1
Department store design OS 6-F3
Service station design OS 6-F3
E. R. Squibb and Sons executive offices OS 6-F3
E. R. Squibb and Sons sales office OS 6-F3
Eagle Pencil Co. OS 1-A6
Eisig residence (Tuckahoe, NY) OS 2-C4
Equitable Trust Co. OS 2-C7
Ettinger residence (Connecticut) OS 3-C12
Fairview Country Club OS 4-E5
Federation building OS 1-A4
Film center OS 2-A9
Fort Greene houses (Brooklyn, NY) OS 5-E7
Garfunkel residence (New York) OS 3-C12
General Cigar building, New York World's Fair OS 6-F3
General Transportation Casualty and Surety Co. OS 3-C12
Glen Oaks Golf and Country Club OS 4-E4
Gowanus houses OS 5-E7
Greenebaum apartment (New York) OS 5-E7
Harris residence (New York) OS 3-E1
Hellman residence (New York) OS 4-E3
Hoffman residence (New York) OS 5-E10
Holland Plaza building OS 4-E6
Hospital for Joint Diseases OS 3-D1
Housing projet (Mineville, NY) OS 5-E7
Huyler's (Buffalo) OS 4-E6
Huyler's (Chicago) OS 4-E6
Insurance Center building OS 2-A7
International Telephone building (Broad and Beaver Streets) OS 2-A8
Jacob Ruppert Distributing Plant OS 5-E7
Jacobs residence OS 5-E7
Jay-Thorpe, Inc. OS 1-A5
Johns-Manville building OS 6-F3
Kahn and Feldman OS 1-A6
Kahn residence (Elmsford, NY) OS 3-E1
Kahn residence (New York) OS 3-E1
Karpen residence (New Rochelle, NY) OS 2-C4
Kohler Company building OS 6-F3
Kolman residence (New York, NY) OS 2-C7
Kridel residence (New York) OS 4-E3
L. P. Hollander and Co. OS 5-E10
Lefcourt Clothing Center OS 2-A9
Lefcourt Empire Building OS 1-A2
Lefcourt Madison Building OS 1-A2
Lefcourt State building OS 2-A8
Lehn and Fink OS 1-A6
Leron, Inc. OS 4-E4
Lexington Ave. and 57th St., southeast corner OS 5-E10
Lexington Park Project OS 5-E7
Liebman residence OS 2-C6
Longchamps Restaurant OS 5-E10
Madison Ave. and 49th St, southwest corner OS 2-A8
Maillard's (Chicago) OS 3-E2
Marshall residence (New York) OS 5-E10
Mausoleums OS 5-E10
Merit Hosiery Co. OS 1-A6
Millinery Center building (New York) OS 5-E9
Montefiore home OS 3-D1
Morgenthau residence (New Jersey) OS 5-E10
Morgenthau residence (New York) OS 5-E10
N.Y. Furniture Exchange OS 1-A2
National Urban League OS 3-D1
New York City Department of Sanitation OS 6-F3
New York City Garage and Air Raid Shelter OS 3-D1
Paramount Annex OS 5-E10
Parents' Magazine office OS 5-E9
Park-Murray Corporation OS 5-E9
Pinaud building OS 1-A6
Pix Theatre (Longchamps) OS 5-E10
Plaut residence (Elmsford, NY) OS 2-C4
Preliminary sketches OS 7
Quaker Ridge Golf Club OS 4-E5
Reynolds Bar (Georgia) OS 4-E5
Richard Hudnut OS 4-E6
Riesenfeld residence (New York) OS 3-E1
Rose residence (New York) OS 3-C12
Rothschild, Dr. Marcus A. office OS 2-C7
Ruben building OS 1-A3
Satenstein residence (New York) OS 5-E7
Schiff Pavilion, Montefiore home OS 3-D1
Scholle residence OS 4-E5
Schweizer residence (New York) OS 3-E1
Shearith-Israel Synagogue OS 4-E6
Shelton Looms showroom OS 6-F3
Shop of Hazel Kolman, Inc. OS 1-A5
Sidney Blumenthal and Company OS 6-F3
Spiegelberg residence (New York) OS 5-E10
Stauffer Chemical OS 5-E10
Steiger-Vedder Co, OS 1-A5
Strauss Mausoleum OS 6-F3
Tishman residence OS 2-C6
U.G.S. Project OS 3-D1
U.S. Appraisers Stores OS 2-A8
USO buildings OS 3-D1
Van Cleef and Arpels, Inc. OS 4-E4
Voice of America building OS 4-E4
War housing project (Rome, NY) OS 5-E7
Yardley and Co., Ltd. showroom OS 6-F3
Younker, Herman residence (Elmsford, NY) OS 3-E1
Younker, Ira residence (Elmsford, NY) OS 3-E1